Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- File containing: “Pamphlets, Reports and Brochures re: Real Estate, Taxes and Investment”. Among other contents: Arizona Corp. Laws and the Advantages of Incorporating in Arizona, Respective Positions of the ten Calif. Building and Loan Associations, Statements of Assets and Liabilities - Monterey
  - “State of New York, Special Report of the State Tax Commission”. No. 5. Operation of Debt and Tax Rate Limits in the State of N.Y. - a study of the constitutional limitations and their effects upon municipal finance, by Frank Leroy Spangler, 1932. (Box 106, Folder 16)
  - “Biennial Report of the State Board of Equalization for the 86th Fiscal Year, ending and the 87th Fiscal Year, ending June 30, 1936”., June 30, 1935 (Box 106, Folder 17)
  - “California Real Estate Directory”. Brokers and Salemen Volume XVI., Jan. 1 to June 30, 1935. (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - “California Real Estate Directory”. Reference Book, Brokers and Salesmen, and Calif. Real Estate Act. Volume XVII., Jan. 1 to June 30, 1936 (Box 106, Folder 19)
  - “Reference Book and Calif. Real Estate Act, Calif. Business Opportunity Act, Cemetery Brokerage Act”. Volume 2, published, 1939. (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - “Calif. Real Estate Directory”. Reference book, Real Estate Brokers and Salesmen, Calif. Real Estate Act, Calif. Business Opportunity Act, Cemetery Brokerage Act. Volume XVIII., Jan. 1 to June 30, 1937 (Box 106, Folder 21)
  - “Calif. Real Estate Directory”. Brokers and Salemen, Plus the Reference Book and the Acts. Volume XIX., July 1 to Sept. 30, 1938. (Box 106, Folder 22)
  - “State of Calif., Division of Real Estate Directory”. Brokers and Salesmen, Reference Book and Acts. Volume XX., July 1 to Sept. 30, 1939. (Box 106, Folder 23)
  - “State of Calif., Division of Real Estate, Directory of Brokers and Salesmen, ”. Acts, Volume XXI., July 1 to Sept. 30, 1940 (Box 106, Folder 24)
  - “The Work of County Planning Commissions in Calif.”., 4/1/37. (Box 106, Folder 25)
- U.C. Publications, College of Agriculture Berkeley, Calif. “The Late Blight of Celery”. by Stanley S. Rogers. Bulletin No. 208, 1911. (Box 106, Folder 26)
- Dept. of Interior, U.S. Geological Survey “Topographical Maps of Calif. and Nevaca”., July 1, 1914. (Box 106, Folder 27)
- U.S. Dept. of Agriculture - “Reconnaissance Soil Survey of the San Francisco Bay Region, Calif.” by L.C. Holmes, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, and J.W. Nelson, University of Calif., 1917. (Box 106, Folder 28)
  - “Economic Chats on Home Ownership”. Peter Hanson, Autographed., 1932. (Box 106, Folder 29)
  - “P.I. Co. Cash Journal (S/B. Nov.) 1913”., Sept. 1910 - Oct. (Box 107)
  - “Record of Real Estate and Other Property - P.I. Co.”. Mainly ated out some information through with index by location., 12/31, 1890, 11/21, 1894. (Box 108)
  - “Ledger - C.P.H. Agent”. with index., 3/4/1880 to 5/31/1803. (Box 109)
  - “Cash C.P.H. Agent”. New York. No index., 3/4/1880 to 5/31/1883 (Box 110)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Balance Sheets, Nov. 1909 to Sept. 1913. (Box 111)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - Balance sheets of General Ledger, ”., Mar. 1906 to Oct. 1909 (Box 112)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Voucher Record, ”. Reverse chron. order., Oct. 1913 to Dec. 1921 (Box 113)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Voucher Record, ”. Reverse chronological order., Jan. 1922 to July 1930 (Box 114)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Cash Book”. Contains: 1. record of cash received, 2. record of checks drawn, 3. record of bank statements and reconciliations, 4. record of cash disbursed, 1-3 in reverse chronological order. 4 in straight chronological order., Jan. 1923 to Nov. 1929, Feb. 1917 to Dec. 1922, Feb. 1917 to Jan. 1926, Feb. 1914 to August 1923. (Box 115)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Cash Book”. Contains: 1. record of cash received 2. record of checks drawn 3. record of bank statements, Jan. - Dec. 1930, Oct. 1929 to March 1931, Aug. - Dec. 1930. (Box 116)
  - “Financial Statements - Pacific Improvement Company”., March 1926 to August 1930. (Box 117)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Cash Book”. Chart of Accts. inside cover, record of receipts through incl., record of disbursements through record of bank statements through, Jan. 1931 1965 Jan. 1931 Dec. 31, 1965, Jan. 1931 Jan. 1941. (Box 118)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Subsidiary Ledger”. record of notes payable and notes receivable., Dates range 1918 - 1926 (Box 119)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. Subsidiary Ledger, 1916”. Record of notes payable and notes receivable., Dates range 11/30/10 - 7/1/19. (Box 120)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - General Ledger ”., Jan. 1, 1917 to Dec. 31, 1922 (Box 121)
  - “Pacific Improvement Co. - General Ledger”. Includes: chart of acct. (inside cover), journal entries ledger accounts expenses and revenues, (1930 - 1965), (1929 - 1965), (1919 - 1965). (Box 122)
- Real Estate Ledger - P.I. Co., index to contents - Alta Vista Tract, San Francisco and Pacific Grove land. Transportation account., 1918 - 1920 (Box 123)
- Real Estate Ledger - P.I. Co., Alta Vista Tract - records of deferred land payments, commissions contingent and taxes receivable Record of accounts receivable - S.F., 1921 - 1929. 1921 - 1923. (Box 124)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 1 - Reedley, Lindsay, Modesto, For items 125-139 and 142-144, deeds are recorded by blocks within townships, and inside each front cover is an index and maps. (Box 125)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 2 - Dinuba, Exeter, Gregg Tractor Parks Orchard. (Box 126)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 3 - Fowler, Coalinga, Cross Landing. (Box 127)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 4 - Lemoore, Benson, Battle Mtn., Ingomar. (Box 128)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 5 - Merced, Lovelock, Montpellier. (Box 129)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 6 - Santa Margarita, Gridley, Montague, Caliente, Nelson. (Box 130)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 7 - Sanger and Boulder Creek. (Box 131)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 8 - Firebaugh, Dos Palos, Porterville, Saticoy. (Box 132)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 9 - Kern County. (Box 133)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 10 - Kern County, East Sec. 28, Virginia, Mojave, Tehachapi, Famosa, Herndon., 1/2 (Box 134)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 11 - Hanford, Armona, El Verano, Westley, Butler. (Box 135)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 12 - Newman, Hickman, Huron. (Box 136)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 13 - Mendota, Tracy, Nord, Irrigosa. (Box 137)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 14 - Session, Orland, Winnumucca, Monson. (Box 138)
- P.I. Co. Record of Deeds Volume 15 - Palermo, San Miguel. (Box 139)
- P.I. Co. Receipt Books, Carbon Hill Coal Co.-Cancelled Checks and Vouchers. (Box 140)
- Pacific Improvement Co. Receipt Books containing copies of receipts for: a. receipt # 51 - 1000, 19 books, b. receipt # 8051 - 9100, 34 books., Jan. 20 - Dec. 12, 1916, May 8, 1926 - Oct. 15, 1928 (Box 140, Folder 1)
- Three sample receipt books (blank), with heading: San Francisco, Cal. _____, 191_. (Box 140, Folder 2)
- Carbon Hill Coal Co. Cancelled checks:, Dec. 12, 1923 - Jan. 24, 1925. (Box 140, Folder 3)
- Carbon Hill Coal Co. Vouchers: for same time period, roughly, 1923 - 1925. (Box 140, Folder 4)
- P.I. Co. Cancelled Checks, Vouchers, Deed Receipts and Del Monte Lodge Forwarding Addresses.
- Bundle of Pacific Improvement Co. checks, (Nos. 10972 - 14579)., Jan. 1930 to Dec. 1940 (Box 141, Folder 1)
- Bundle of Pacific Improvement Co. checks, Jan. 1941 - Dec. 1955. (Box 141, Folder 2)
- Bundle of Pacific Improvement Co. checks, Jan. 1956 - Dec. 1965. (Box 141, Folder 3)
- Bundle of Pacific Improvement Co. vouchers, Jan. 1929 - Dec. 31, 1933. (Box 141, Folder 4)
- Bundle of Pacific Improvement Co. vouchers, Jan. 1934 to March 1936. (Box 141, Folder 5)
- Bundle of Pacific Improvement Co. Vouchers, April 1936 to Dec. 1940. (Box 141, Folder 6)
- Bundle of P.I. Co. vouchers, Jan. 1, 1941 to Dec. 31, 1945. (Box 141, Folder 7)
- Bundle of P.I. Co. vouchers, Jan. 1, 1946 to Dec. 31, 1950. (Box 141, Folder 8)
- Bundle of P.I. Co. Journal vouchers, Jan. 1951 to Dec. 1955. (Box 141, Folder 9)
- Bundle of P.I. Co. vouchers, Jan. 1956 - Dec. 1960. (Box 141, Folder 10)
- Bundle of P.I. Co. vouchers, (liquidation)., Jan. 1961 to 1968 (Box 141, Folder 11)
- Bundle of P.I. Co. Deed Receipts, June 1923 to May 1929. (Box 141, Folder 12)
- Bundle of index cards of Forwarding Addresses for Del Monte Lodge Guests (alphabetical). (Box 141, Folder 13)
- BOOKS
  - P.I. Co. Record of Deeds, Volume 16 - Wells, Carlin, Traver. (Box 142)
  - P.I. Co. Record of Deeds, Volume 17 - Tipon, Waterford, Fruto, Maxwell. (Box 143)
  - P.I. Co. Record of Deeds, Volume 18 - Delano, Newhall, Addition to Montague, Amsterdam. (Box 144)
  - P.I. Co. Record of Deeds, Volume 19 - Pebble Beach. (Box 145)
  - P.I. Co. Record of Deeds, Volume 20 - Alta Vista Tract, Addition to Wells, East Fresno, Hope Ranch Park. (Box 146)
    - “Pacific Grove, 3, P.I. Co.”. Record of deeds by block, with index., dates: 6/30/1887 to 1/18/1915 (Box 147)
    - “Deed Book, No. 7”. Record of deeds issued by P.I. Co., in all townships arranged chronologically With index., 4/17/06 - 1/2/1918. (Box 148)
    - “Deed Book, 8”. Record of deeds issued by P.I. Co., all townships arranged chronologically With index., 1/4/18 - 5/27/1966. (Box 149)
    - “Document Register”. For all P.I. Co. Documents. Index of document forms in front cover, sample of document forms in back cover, index and register., Dates: Oct. 1917 - May 1922. (Box 150)
    - “Town Lot Receipts - Pacific Improvement Co.”. Record of receipts -, Jan. 1910 to March 1912. (Box 151)
    - “Town Lot Receipts - P.I. Co.”. Record of receipts -, April 1912 to Dec. 1913. (Box 152)
  - P.I. Co. Real Estate - Stetement of Accounts with index., 1909 - May 1922 (Box 153)
  - Record of Deeds issued by P.I. Co. to lands in following townsites: Fresno, Tulare, Merced, Modesto, Sumner, Delano, Lathrop, Tracy, Oakland, Niles. Arranged by townsites (in above order) and chronologically by townsite., Dates: 1875 - 1884. (Box 154)
    - “Alta Vista Tract General Ledger”. Referred Land Payments, General Accounts, Commissions, Building Discounts. Dates of entries range, 1914 - 1930. (Box 155)
    - “Day Book”. For P.I. Co. includes records of town lot receipts, balances due on contracts, outstanding contracts, Oakland Water Front Co., 1906 (Box 156)
    - “Journal, Alta Vista Tract”., May 1914 to Dec. 31, 1921. (Box 157)
    - “Journal, Alta Vista Tract, Jan. 1, 1922 to July 31, 1930”. (Box 158)
    - “Journal, Land Department”. P.I. Co., 10/1/1913 - 12/31/15. (Box 159)
  - P.I. Co. Ledger recording rate of rent or interest received from various businesses and land., Dates 1907 - 1913. (Box 160)
  - P.I. Co. Ledger showing the blocks and lots in the town of El Verano which remained unsold as of, April 21, 1914. (Box 161)
    - “Document Register No. 1”. For P.I. Co. Documents. Entries handwritten and signed by George Stimmel. Arranged chronologically, with typed index., dates: 6/26/1916 to 12/6/1916. (Box 162)
    - “Document Register No. 3.”. For P.I. Co. Documents. Entries handwritten and signed by J. Beaumont, Arranged chronologically, with index., dates: 8/10/17 to 11/14/17. (Box 163)
  - P.I. Co. Business Papers
  - Maps of Carbon Hill Coal Co. Carbonado, Washington. (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - “Indenture Del Monts Properties Co. to Anglo-Calif. Trust Co., Trustee”. Securing $2,000,000, First Mortgage Sinking Fund Six Per Cent Gold Bonds, interest payable, dated: April 1, 1925, April 1 and Oct. 1. (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - “The Monterey County Water Works to Anglo-Calif. Trust Co., Trustee”. First Mortgage, dated: Oct. 1, 1925. (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - “U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Weather Bureau - Summary of Climatological Data for the United States by Sections. Reprint of Section 14 - Central & Southern Calif. (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - “Report of the Power, Irrigation and Domestic Water Supply Possibilities of the Carmel River, Monterey, Calif.”. By J.A. Wilcox., 1/18/1918. (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - “Timber Estimates and General Dta”. Relative to the valuation and disposition of the properties of the Pacific Improvement Co. in the vicinity of Castle Crag., Calif. made by F.J. Solinsky, Jr. (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - “Copy of Abstract of Title to Property in Alameda Marsh”. Prepared for the Oakland Water Front Co, dated: 11/6/1916. (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - “Copy of Abstract of Title to Property in Alameda Marsh”. Prepared for the Oakland Water Front Co., dated:, 3/14/1912. (Box 164, Folder 8)
    - “Special Report on the Liquidation of the Pacific Improvement Co. and Affiliated Companies., Oct. 31, 1923. (Box 164, Folder 9)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Monthly Report ”., March 1925 (Box 164, Folder 10)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Monthly Report ”., June 1925 (Box 164, Folder 11)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Monthly Report ”., Sept. 1925 (Box 164, Folder 12)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Annual Report ”., 1925 (Box 164, Folder 13)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Monthly Report ”., March 1926 (Box 164, Folder 14)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Monthly Report ”., June 1926 (Box 164, Folder 15)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Monthly Report ”., Sept. 1926 (Box 164, Folder 16)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. ”., March 1927 (Box 164, Folder 17)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. ”., June 1927 (Box 164, Folder 18)
    - “Pacific Improvement Co. Annual Report ”., 1929 (Box 164, Folder 19)